Millions of us grab a coffee on our way to work.
我们中的数百万人在上班的路上会买一杯咖啡。
And when we do, it probably comes served in a branded, disposable, cardboard coffee cup.
当我们买咖啡时，咖啡可能是装在一个有品牌的、一次性的（disposable）纸质咖啡杯里。
Once the coffee is done, just pop the cup into a recycling bin and forget about it.
一旦喝完咖啡，就把杯子扔进回收垃圾桶，然后就不再管它了。
The cup will be taken away and turned into a new one for you to use again tomorrow.
这个杯子会被收走，然后变成一个新的杯子，供你明天再次使用。
The system works, right?
这个系统可行，对吧？
There’s a hitch.
但有个问题。
In the UK, we throw away an estimated 2.5 billion disposable coffee cups every year.
在英国，据估计我们每年会扔掉25亿个一次性咖啡杯。
And despite being recyclable in theory, in practice only very few of them are dealt with in a way that makes them sustainable.
尽管从理论上讲这些杯子是可回收的，但实际上只有极少数杯子以一种可持续的方式得到处理。
This makes them a bit of an obstacle.
这使它们成为了一个障碍。
What throws a spanner in the works is the layer of polyethylene that makes the cup waterproof, and the lid, which is most often made of polystyrene.
妨碍计划顺利进行（throws a spanner）的是使杯子防水的聚乙烯层，以及通常由聚苯乙烯制成的杯盖。
As a result, most of the cups end up in landfill.
结果，大多数杯子最终都被填埋了。
But there are efforts underway to tackle this issue.
但目前已经在努力解决这个问题。
One company, Biome Bioplastics, has come up with a fully compostable, recyclable cup that uses natural materials, such as potato starch, as waterproofing.
一家名为生物群落生物塑料的公司想出了一种完全可堆肥的（compostable）、可回收的杯子，这种杯子使用天然材料，例如土豆淀粉，来作为防水材料。
Mr Mines, its chief executive, believes that this is the first time bioplastic has been used for disposable cups and lids that have to cope with hot liquid. And they're still fully recyclable.
该公司的首席执行官迈恩斯（Mines）先生认为，这是生物塑料首次被用于必须盛装热饮的一次性杯子和杯盖，而且它们仍然是完全可回收的。
Another feasible solution has been proposed by Frugalpac, who have patented a cup with a lightly-attached plastic lining.
另一个切实可行的解决方案是由弗鲁加尔帕克（Frugalpac）公司提出的，他们已经为一种带有轻度附着塑料衬里的杯子申请了专利。
This can be easily separated during the recycling and ‘offers a more pragmatic solution’ than changing our current recycling habits, says Frugalpac’s founder Martin Myerscough.
弗鲁加尔帕克公司的创始人马丁・迈尔斯考夫（Martin Myerscough）说，这种衬里在回收过程中可以很容易地分离，并且“提供了一个比改变我们目前的回收习惯更实用可行的解决方案”。
Safia Qureshi says India has provided the inspiration for her solution.
萨菲亚・库雷希（Safia Qureshi）说，印度为她的解决方案提供了灵感。
She puts forward that we use returnable and reusable cups, which are tracked and collected by her company Cup Club.
她提议我们使用可退还和可重复使用的杯子，这些杯子由她的公司“杯子俱乐部”（Cup Club）进行追踪和收集。
They will be responsible for collecting, washing and redistributing the clean cups to participating retailers.
该公司将负责收集、清洗这些干净的杯子，并将它们重新分发给参与的零售商。
One final example of lateral thinking comes from Cupffee.
最后一个横向思维的例子来自“杯啡”（Cupffee）公司。
This trio from Bulgaria have combined cereals to form a cup which can be eaten once the drink is finished.
这个来自保加利亚的三人团队将谷物组合在一起，制成了一种杯子，喝完饮料后这种杯子可以被吃掉。
It is apparently sweet and crisp, can hold a coffee for up to 40 minutes and will biodegrade within weeks.
它显然是香甜且酥脆的，能盛装咖啡长达40分钟，并且会在几周内生物降解。
Whether any of these innovative ideas are a perfect fit for this disposable issue, only time will tell.
这些创新想法中是否有任何一个完全适合解决一次性杯子的问题，只有时间能告诉我们答案。
It’s possible that a more viable solution has yet to be ventured, though it may not be long in coming.
可能还有一个更切实可行的解决方案尚未被尝试，不过它可能很快就会出现。
All it may require is a little more thinking outside the box… or should that be coffee cup?
这可能只需要再多一点跳出常规的思考……或者应该说是跳出咖啡杯的思考？